Oleksandr Boiko

Senior Software Engineer with 10+ years of experience in designing and developing various enterprise Web-applications and services.

Always trying to keep up with latest technologies, constantly improving my skills and searching for opportunities of introducing new solutions.

EXPERIENCE

ZyLAB, Amsterdam — Senior Software Engineer

2015 - PRESENT

Involved in a huge enterprise eDiscovery product as a full-stack developer. Refactoring and implementing a new functionality in documents processing system. Implementing a set of integration tests to cover concurrency scenarios. Responsible for research and prototyping of a modern UI based on HTML5 and JavaScript (Typescript).

MedeAnalytics, Kharkiv, Ukraine — *Lead Software Engineer*

2013 - 2015

Created a new team and led a rapid development of new functionality for multitenant web-based SaaS application for analysis of big data and reporting. Took part in all aspects of the project lifecycle from planning and business analysis to system design, implementation, and deployment. Developed and successfully delivered a set of new features, also improved performance and simplified configuration of the product.

Manenburgdreef 67 Hoofddorp, 2135GV +3165-750-7293 olek.boiko@gmail.com

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

C#, JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL, Html, Css, Powershell.

FRAMEWORKS AND TECHS

Angular (1-2), React.js, Rx.js, Jasmine, Knockout.js, jQuery, Asp.net (MVC and Classic), WCF, RabbitMQ, Redis, MongoDb, Entity Framework.

CERTIFICATION

Microsoft

- Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3 (480)
- MCPD: Web Developer .Net 4 (519)

EPAM, Kharkiv, Ukraine — Senior Software Engineer

2011 - 2013

Participated in four different projects as backend and frontend developer. Design and implementation of real-time web-based application/widgets for monitoring trading events from stock market.

Development of backend data access and processing layers, windows services, WCF services. Developed agile working process and established productive relations with customer. Interviewed new developers.

Stella Systems, Kharkiv, Ukraine — Software Engineer \rightarrow Lead Software Engineer

2005 - 2011

Contributed to development of various parts of huge enterprise Web-application including backend services and frontend Web UI. Developed modules for analysis of historical data retrieved from OLAP and building forecasting reporting. Implemented exports to PDF, Excel. Developed lots of specific UI components for reporting, filtering and managing of hierarchical data structures.

Participated in QCon San Francisco 2008. Enforced SCRUM process establishment in the company. Collaborated with a 20-member international software team. Consulting and helping for newcomers.

Freelance, Kharkiv, Ukraine — *Developer*

2004 - 2005

Worked for offshore team developing software for Canadian drilling industry.

Developed Web-service for communicating with other enterprise applications, UI for touch devices, data access layer, exports to PDF, Excel and Printing. Implementation of SSL tunnel for ODBC driver for secure database connection.

PROJECTS

JavaScript Map Parser — Open Source, Owner, Developer

2007 - 2013

Developed an extension for Visual Studio and Notepad++ that shows a map for JavaScript code in a separate panel. Got more than 250K downloads and 50 five-star reviews.

EDUCATION

National Technical University 'Kharkiv Polytechnic Institute', Kharkiv, Ukraine

2001 - 2007

Master's degree. Applied mathematics and computer science. Diploma thesis: Development of a cryptographic system based on RC5 encryption and RSA digital signature.